Epris Richardson

Mooresville, NC, US ≅ eharrisburnett@gmail.com ☐ 248-730-8645 in in/eprishb ♠ https://www.eprisr.com

SUMMARY

Experienced Front End Developer with 5 years in crafting exceptional online experiences through developing user-friendly websites. Partners with designers and back-end developers to build high-performing web applications, retaining UI/UX. Proficient in marketing tool integration, boosting web traffic.

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer | WECO Hospitality

July 2022 - August 2023, Acton, MA

- Teamed up with a small cross-functional team in enhancing the technology stack to transition an online application from WordPress to React in 6 months, improving the application's security, speed, and scalability using Agile software development.
- Improved UX by ensuring real-time updates and seamless data synchronization between the client and server by implementing data handling, posting and fetching data from the backend API using Axios.
- Aided in integrating Google Maps and Autocomplete APIs for seamless, user-friendly pickup and delivery address selection.
- Integrated Google Analytics to gain valuable insights into user behavior, product performance, and application usage, leading to data-driven decisions for continuous improvement.
- Enhanced ad targeting and conversions by setting up Google Ads and Tag Manager, streamlining campaign tracking and user interactions.

Web Developer & Graphic Designer | BROOKS EQUIPMENT / BHC ISS

February 2019 - July 2022, Charlotte, NC

- Collaborated with IT in building two eCommerce sites and a service site from the ground up in 1 year and migrated an eCommerce site using best practices.
- Trained and mentored junior developer in department practices and common tasks such as updating certain pages in websites and optimizing PDFs for faster load time in flipbooks.
- Adapted Google Marketing Platform. (Analytics, Tag Manager) and Google Search Console into eCommerce sites for eCommerce tracking and SEO, Increasing web traffic by 6 7%.
- Maintained seven company sites, updating UI/UX, accessibility, and optimizing for touch devices and SEO.
- Mentored designers on basic HTML & CSS markup for product pages, email templates, and marketing materials.

Project Manager | APPLET SOCIAL

September 2014 - May 2018, Detroit, MI

• Designed and prototyped layouts in Adobe XD to later be developed.

• Acquired two clients, consistently communicating to develop a project brief around business needs and provide guidance in the overall process.

PROJECTS

My Reads - React Application

https://my-reads-eprishb.herokuapp.com/

• Developed React Application with "React Thinking", design patterns and using JavaScript ES6 features.

Neighborhood Map - React Application

https://neighborhood-map-eprishb.herokuapp.com/

• Integrated Google Maps and Foursquare APIs into a React application, using JavaScript and third-party libraries in order to render and access the data from each of the called APIs, while creating a responsive UI.

Memory Game - JS Application

https://eprisr.github.io/Project-Memory_Game/

• Used Object-Oriented Programming, JavaScript methods and properties to build a Memory Game that is fully responsive and accessible.

EDUCATION

BFA - Visual Communications | Art Institute of Michigan

Novi, MI

AAS - Graphic Design | The Art Institute of Michigan

Troy, MI, 2014

CERTIFICATIONS

Computer Science for Web Programming | HarvardX

In-Progress

Front-End Web Development Nanodegree | Udacity

2018

SKILLS

JavaScript, Typescript, React, Next.JS, Remix, Express.Js, Lodash, Bootstrap, Jest, React Testing Library, Mock Service Worker, MongoDB, Firebase, Git, Github, AWS Code Commit, Hubspot, Google Marketing Platform, SEO, Heroku, Sentry, Trello, Shortcut, HTML5/CSS3